[distorted vocalizing]
[water dripping]
[metal clanging]
[electricity crackling]
[machinery whirring]
[faint chatter on radio]
[gasps] Fuck me.
[Siberian] Hey.
Who does surgery on a crashing ship?
I don't think they died in the crash.
Look at their faces.
Looks like suffocation.
Or cabin depressurized, maybe.
Suddenly they're breathing space.
No, see the blue lips?
Some kind of toxin.
Whoa.
He had some kind of foreign bodies
lining his GI tract.
There's an incident code.
1562.
Looks like they're gone now.
Okay, come on.
We're search and rescue.
Let forensics Agatha Christie this shit.
Search and rescue!
[Hermit] Rashidi.
1562, foreign bodies…
-Yeah, you said that.
-[electricity crackling]
It's bad.
Bad how?
Wait, what do you mean foreign?
Alien.
[sighs] This day just
gets better and better.
Up or down?
[Rashidi] Chief said to go down,
so we're going down.
Let's move.
[Siberian] Hey.
[Marcy] Well, I really like Wendy because
I know that she's like a big sister to me,
like one I never had,
and I know that everyone is really kind
and I love all the children.
[child 1] I'm really looking forward
to not being sick anymore.
It's really bad.
I really hate it.
[child 2] I can't wait to be so smart
and so intelligent.
I could solve any problem.
I'm excited…
I'm scared, but it's…
I think it'll be worth it. [laughs]
[Boy Kavalier] Such potential.
[chews] People say that
about children. Hmm?
What they could be.
You're talking about achievement.
But it's about becoming.
Teaching them to be their best selves.
Uh-huh.
[bites, chews]
The fear with
artificial intelligence is that,
you know,
we will build a brilliant machine
that will build an even smarter machine,
so on…
Until so long us. [chews]
What we're doing here, you and me,
is exploding human potential.
Then we'll see what they build
before the machines ruin everything.
It's an intelligence race.
But if they don't stay human,
then what did we win?
I'm serious.
We did something
nobody thought was possible.
-We ended death.
-Hmm.
Now we have to make
their quality of life better,
otherwise all we've done
is make consumers immortal.
It's not about money.
People always think
it's about money with trillionaires.
Or ego.
But you know… [stammers] …you know
what I really want?
I wanna talk to somebody smarter than me.
Thanks.
Yeah, I mean, you're smart.
[smacks lips] You're just not smarter.
And Kirsh?
Kirsh is information smart.
Data cross-references with the musings
of every great philosopher,
but that's not wisdom.
For once in my life,
I want to climb to the top of the mountain
and debate with someone who blows my mind.
[chomps, chewing]
And you think that's the children.
Maybe.
At the very least, my hope is that…
[inhales sharply]
…by giving Wendy
a supercomputer for a brain
and training by the best geniuses
money can buy,
I'll finally be able to have
an interesting fucking conversation.
Did a ship really crash?
Are there gonna be dead bodies?
Don't…
Don't think about that.
What are you thinking about?
It's a secret.
Okay?
I have a brother.
And he works in the city.
He's a-a medic, like a doctor?
[chuckles] And he's really good at it too.
And he's down there
right now saving lives,
but what if… [sighs]
He's not like us, Slightly.
He's not premium.
He can break and bleed and-and burn,
and I made him stay.
So I'm gonna find him.
My dad got a cold and died in Mumbai.
And we burned him on this pyre,
which is very holy.
But every night after, I worry,
what if he's not dead?
And… And we burned him anyway.
[Kirsh] Ready yourselves.
Gear up.
Don't worry. We'll find him.
-Find who?
-Her brother. He's a doctor down there.
Secret.
-[Slightly chuckles]
-[Smee grunts]
[sighs]
We're gonna have to jump.
-[Siberian] Fuck that.
-[Rashidi shouts]
[grunts, groaning]
[Hermit chuckles]
[Rashidi] Si, come on.
[exhales sharply] Watch this.
[grunting]
-[Rashidi groaning]
-[Siberian screams]
-[Rashidi] Siberian!
-[Siberian grunts]
[grunts]
-Don't you fucking drop me.
-I got you. [grunts]
[Siberian grunts]
[both panting]
[Siberian chuckles]
-Hermit.
-[breathing heavily]
Yo! Haul ass!
[whispering] All right. Okay.
-[Hermit] Oh, shit.
-[hisses]
[creature screeches]
[screaming]
[screams]
[gasps, breathing heavily]
This is Hermit. Come in.
[breathing heavily]
This is Prodigy medic Hermit. Come in.
Requesting backup.
I'm on the-the south elevator.
I'm heading up.
There's a… [stammers] …creature,
she's… [breathes heavily] …loose,
approximately eight feet tall.
Armored. [breathes heavily]
Does anyone read me?
Fuck. Fuck.
Okay.
[grunting]
[automated voice]
Now serving number 21801.
[robot] Prodigy medic Hermit,
please state the reason
for your visit today.
Yeah, I'm following up
on forms I submitted on resigning.
[clicks]
Please stand by, Prodigy medic Hermit.
The unit is reviewing your request.
According to your file, you have
seven months remaining on your contract.
Right.
I'm asking special dispensation
on account of…
Because I made a promise to my father
that I'd go back to medical school.
Father: Frank J. Hermit.
Died January 16 of last year.
Yeah, he was the last surviving…
It's a long story.
Isn't there a person I could talk to?
A human?
Look, I've been wounded twice and…
[Kirsh] She's watching him every day.
Sometimes two or three times.
I gotta move on.
I gotta keep my promise.
You think it was a mistake
to give her access?
[Hermit] To live up to my…
I think it's distracting.
It soothes her.
It's favoritism.
There's a spot for me.
See? At school, medical school on Mars.
They gave me a scholarship,
but classes start next month, so…
I'm the last one, okay?
I have to do this now.
[whirs]
I have to do it now.
[sighs] Have a heart.
Or face my fury.
[whirring]
[robot] Face your furry what?
What did you say?
Did she just…
What just happened? [typing]
Uh, s-she rewrote the code somehow.
She… Did we know?
Did we give her that, uh, skill?
Uh, she's connected to the Prodigy network
so we could monitor her settings
and data streams in both directions, but
it never occurred to us that she would…
[Hermit] What did you say?
Did you just…
Thank you, Prodigy medic Hermit.
Your request has been denied.
You will complete your contractually
agreed upon time in this location.
Have a productive day.
[whirring]
[sirens wailing]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[radio chatter continues]
[sirens wailing continues]
[buzzing]
[buzzing continues]
Do you hear that?
What?
It's like a buzzing.
[buzzing]
[soldiers chattering]
[horn honking]
Colonel Nagg, crisis response team.
Kirsh, chief scientist, Prodigy One.
[buzzing]
This way.
[sirens wailing]
[Nagg] It's a 100-story tower.
Eighty floors above ground, 20 below.
Comms are still down.
Damage report still coming in.
I'm worried about the gas lines, fires.
I'm also worried about the fuel source
on the ship, that it's unstable.
[Slightly and Smee grunting]
The ammunition, insecure.
Don't get me started on radiation.
They promised us reinforcements
from the city three hours ago,
and all I see is you seven.
[Kirsh] We're a special unit
here under orders from the founder.
[Nagg] What kind of orders?
You don't need to know that.
[Ops Hamm] Hey.
Chief.
-What is she doing?
-You have a medic in your unit? Hermit?
[Ops Hamm] He's on Rashidi's team.
They haven't checked in.
Benjamin Rashidi, 32, sergeant.
What is she doing?
What floor is this?
[Ops Hamm] Sixty-five.
Wendy? Wendy.
Slightly,
go with her.
-Me?
-The rest of you on me.
We're moving fast.
Assess the damage, rescue survivors.
I want GPS on wounded
reported back to command.
[newscaster on monitor
speaks indistinctly]
…more medics are en route now.
As we get updates,
we'll be letting you know.
Emergency response are scanning
for life signs, but no…
[chuckles]
[sighs, chuckles] They're down.
Data's pouring in.
Feels like Christmas.
Sir, I have Yutani on the line.
[sighs]
[beeps]
It's been a very expensive day.
Yeah, you're telling me.
Not to mention lives lost.
Of course.
You have something that belongs to me.
Uh, to be fair, it fell from the sky
and broke one of my buildings.
Reparations will be made.
Just send us a bill.
My men are on site now securing the crash.
Is there anything we need to know, uh,
about the ship?
A deep space research vessel.
It goes without saying that everything
on board should be considered proprietary.
I'd like permission to send a team.
To secure the ship and remove what's ours.
I'm… um, I'm afraid
I can't allow that just yet.
You know that the, um,
tower is still too unstable.
And I'm afraid I must insist.
Um, I don't have to remind
you that… [sighs]
…any incursion onto Prodigy territory
will be construed as a hostile act.
This is what lawyers are for.
You know, you have yours talk to mine,
and then we'll negotiate
a treaty. [chuckles]
Now, excuse me. I'm needed elsewhere.
Predictable.
I want what's on that ship.
[chuckles]
[electricity crackling]
[garbled audio plays on speakers]
[buzzing]
[thinking] Something's here.
I miss baths.
I used to hate baths, but now I miss them.
Quiet now.
[chirping]
Fear is for animals.
You are not animals.
Now move.
[ship creaking]
[clicking sound]
-Fascinating.
-I want to go home now.
It looks like a plant.
It's a monster. Let's kill it.
Scientists don't kill.
Careful.
This is a non-terrestrial species.
[Kirsh] We don't know
what it's capable of.
[Boy Kavalier chuckles, grunts]
Curly, you're on point.
Take Smee and Nibs and see if you can find
something to capture it with.
[Curly] Nibs, don't look.
Yo, what is that?
[squelching]
[creature squeals]
Ah. Monster.
[whimpers]
-Monster. M-Monsters! [whimpers]
-[Nibs whimpers]
We should…
Weren't we supposed to catch it?
-[Smee whimpers] Wait, was that blood?
-[glass shatters]
Uh, there's more.
[Smee] Whoa. Gross.
[Nibs] Ugh…
[purrs]
[growls]
[meows]
[squawks, screeches softly]
[growling, grunting]
-[Smee whimpering] No! No!
-[Curly] Hey! Hey! [shrieks]
[gasps, grunts]
-Hey! Hey!
-[screaming]
-[Curly] Throw it down!
-[Nibs shrieks]
Nibs, please, please, please.
-Oh!
-[clattering]
[exhales]
What is that?
[squeaks]
He was this way.
Yuck!
-Ugh.
-Are those…
Are those scratches?
Like fingernails?
Like claws.
Bear claws.
Wait. There are bears?
[radio static]
This is Prodigy medic Hermit.
Come in. [breathing heavily]
Rashidi, Siberian.
Does anybody read me?
Bergerfeld.
Where the fuck is everybody?
Comms are down.
This whole building feels
like it's about to collapse.
Have you seen any animals?
-Animals? What sort of animals?
-Like, uh, big animals.
Like pets?
No, definitely not like pets.
[people laughing]
I've cleared all the other apartments
on this floor.
[Hermit grunts, breathes heavily]
[Hermit] Search and rescue!
[Bergerfeld] Security services! Open up!
[laughing continues]
[British accent] The noise. So much noise.
Sir, we're evacuating the building.
Please find the nearest elevator
and head down.
We're having a dinner party.
The Caspians are here.
There's a spaceship in the lobby.
I think the Caspians will understand.
Well, I'm sure if it's a real problem,
Boy Kavalier will call me personally.
We belong to the same club.
Well, sir, I don't know about that.
I do know that the north stairwell is out
and that the fire suppression system
is down,
and until we can check
the structure of the building--
Sir!
[pounding on door]
Move.
[heavy footsteps]
[hissing]
-[creature screeches]
-[rapid gunfire]
What the--
Oh, my dear! [screaming]
-[screams]
-[screeches]
[grunts]
[His Lordship and guests screaming]
[grunts, pants]
-[creature shrieking]
-[screaming]
-[person screams]
-[body thuds]
[panting]
[creature hisses]
[helicopter passing]
[wind whistling]
[His Lordship] The noise… noise…
So much noise.
[grunts]
[muttering] So much noise.
[Hermit grunting]
[creature shrieks]
[screaming]
[hissing]
[screeches]
[Hermit panting]
[panting]
[Hermit grunts]
Thank you.
[weapon clicks]
[fluid dripping]
[chirping]
It presents as flora, but it may be fauna.
[Smee] Kirsh. Kirsh?
Stay here.
Keep an eye on this.
[Smee] Kirsh?
[Smee] Kirsh!
Uh, it was… it was in the cat.
What was in the cat?
[Nibs] Don't!
It's fast.
[computer beeps]
[Curly] It's like a zoo,
but the animals got out.
[sighs]
It's a research vessel.
Deep space model.
They must have been collecting specimens.
[stammers] I thought
specimens meant "dead."
[elevator bell dings]
[Morrow grunting]
[radio chatter]
[Cortez] Sir, you need
to leave the building now.
The stairs are blocked,
so I thought I could--
There's been a crash.
Everyone has to go now.
Of course.
-I just need to know which way--
-[Brahma] What's in the bag?
Supplies.
-What the fuck?
-Hands!
-Just calm down.
-Hands. Now!
You're making a mistake.
[Brahma] Shit. He's a cyborg.
Don't move. Don't blink.
Damn.
Just stay calm, friend.
They can sense fear.
[Cortez] I'm not your friend.
[Brahma] Put your hands behind your back.
And lock your fingers together now.
Just so you know,
I'm the least of your problems.
-[gunfire]
-[soldiers screaming]
[bodies thudding]
[hissing]
-[hisses]
-[soldier] What the fuck is that?
-[heavy footsteps]
-[soldier] Fuck! Move!
-[heavy running footsteps]
-[soldier] Fuck!
-[soldiers screaming]
-[creature roars]
-Open fire!
-[rapid gunfire]
-[soldiers groaning]
-[creature screeches]
[gasps]
[blade scraping]
[Curly whispers] Hey! Psst.
No, now.
Come on.
-Smee.
-Uh-huh?
I need you there.
You'll link up with Wendy.
Secure the area. Nobody gets in or out
until the hazmat team arrives.
O-Okay.
Whoa.
There is a bear.
-Why?
-Warrior mode.
Ugh.
[young Hermit, Frank] ♪You've got to
Ac-cent-tchu-ate the positive ♪
♪ And e-lim-i-nate the negative ♪
♪ And latch on to the affirmative ♪
♪ But don't mess with… ♪
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[machine clicks]
[crowd cheering]
-Reggie Jackson has seen two pitches…
-Wow.
…in the strike zone tonight.
-Two. And he's hit 'em both in the seats.
-[crowd cheering]
Would you look at that, Dad?
Reggie Jackson, game six,
1977 World Series.
New York Yankees
versus Los Angeles Dodgers.
Reggie Jackson hits three home runs.
-[crowd roars]
-[announcer 1] High and…
-[announcer 2] Goodbye!
-[announcer 3] Goodbye!
[announcer 3] Oh, what a blow!
What a way to top it off!
Forget about who the most
valuable player is in the World Series.
How this man has responded to pressure.
Oh, what a beam on his face.
How can you blame him?
He's answered the whole world.
What are the odds?
[announcer 3]
What a colossal [garbled] blow…
[chuckles]
Who are you talking to?
My dad.
You're hurt.
-[Slightly] Me?
-Let me see.
You talk to Dad?
Uh, well, I know he's not… he's not here.
-But, um…
-[sprayer bottle spritzing]
You see this ball and the game…
We used to watch
the old highlight reels together.
He called it proof.
He said sometimes the world
gives you a moment to shine.
And if you do, well…
There's a name for that kind of hero.
He called him Mr. October.
[chuckles] Mister?
Where's the cut?
[Slightly] There's no cut.
There's a bear.
He ate the men in the hall.
-A bear? [laughs]
-Mm-hmm.
We don't bleed anyway.
Not red anymore.
-Uh…
-It's all white inside.
-You're synthetic.
-Oh, we don't like that word.
You're both synthetic.
No, we're…
-something different.
-Something special.
-[Kirsh] Wendy?
-Yeah, Kirsh, we're here.
We, um… [laughs] …we found him.
I don't care about that.
I need you to get to
the front section of the ship.
-There's cargo I need you to secure.
-Um… [stammers]
[Kirsh] Smee is already en route.
Can it wait?
Can it… No, it can't wait.
These are invasive species.
If we don't lock them down,
they could escape, breed.
And then it will be too late.
We should go.
Smee doesn't like being alone.
-[Kirsh] Stop acting like children.
-[groans]
-[Kirsh] Lives are at stake.
-We're not children anymore.
[Kirsh] You need to go, now.
Will you come with us?
[stammers] I've got to get back.
There will be loads of people there,
bloody, wounded, exploded.
We're going to the front section.
Please?
Okay.
Wendy…
Yeah, okay. I…
Keep up. We move fast.
-[elevator bell dings]
-[electricity crackling]
This way.
[bell dings]
[creature hissing]
Excuse me.
What did he mean
you're not children anymore?
Uh, we are kids.
What… I don't get it.
-I'm 11, and Wendy just turned 12.
-Slightly.
That's you? Your name's Wendy?
No, that's her machine name.
When we were children,
we fell really sick.
Then we were given these big bodies, but
my name's actually Aarush and she's Marcy.
My sister's name is Marcy.
-Dude.
-Don't you dare.
-That's your sister.
-Slightly, secret. Go.
-You weren't telling him.
-Go. Get up there, now.
[sighs]
Joe.
[Wendy chuckles]
It's me.
I found you.
I-I've been watching you
all the time on the screens.
I watch you go to work,
I watch you ride in boats.
You help people.
Face my fury.
You remember?
And I'm sorry. It is my fault.
You wanted to go to Mars.
-And I couldn't… I wouldn't…
-No, no, no.
You died.
I went to the funeral.
No. Daddy…
Daddy said…
Joe, when I was sick,
the boy genius came to visit me.
And he told Daddy that he could help me,
but I had to go away.
So they took me to live
with Kirsh and Dame Sylvia.
I don't understand.
But that was the way.
-Joe.
-[sniffs]
Or I would die.
They said I was special.
Dad told me--
Daddy said don't talk.
[whispers] Daddy said
it had to be a secret.
They said I would be okay.
But I could never go home.
-Who said?
-The boy genius.
His name is on your uniform.
[Slightly] Guys, Kirsh said we gotta go.
Please.
[buzzing]
-Think it's inside.
-Your first day of day care.
Dad picked you up.
You were filthy and your lip was bleeding.
What did you say?
I am mad to them.
-Let me. [grunts]
-[metal scrapes]
I could have done that.
Christmas morning.
You were seven.
You woke me up before the sun.
What did you say?
I still don't think my big toe
looks like my thumb.
[Hermit sighs]
[Slightly] Uh, guys?
[buzzing]
[buzzing continues]
-[buzzing]
-Do you hear that?
I hear the sound of metal bending
like the ship's about to fall.
[creature screeching]
[buzzing]
[distant screeching]
Call it in.
Hmm. Looks like eggs.
And then I think…
-No!
-[Hermit screams]
Joe!
Slightly?
-Should we jump?
-Slightly. Slightly!
Stay here.
Look at me. Stay safe.
-No.
-Guard the omelet.
No, no, no. Wendy!
[♪ "Stinkfist" playing]
♪ Something has to change ♪
♪ Undeniable dilemma ♪
♪ Boredom's not a burden
Anyone should bear ♪
♪ Just not enough, I need more ♪
♪ Nothing seems to satisfy ♪
♪ I said, I don't want it
I just need it ♪
♪ To breathe, to feel, to know I'm alive ♪
♪ Finger deep within the borderline ♪
♪ Show me that you love me
And that we belong together ♪
♪ Relax, turn around and take my hand ♪
♪ I can help you change ♪
♪ Tired moments into pleasure ♪
♪ Say the word and we'll be
Well upon our way ♪
♪ Blend and balance, pain and comfort ♪
♪ Deep within you
Till you will not want me any other way ♪
♪ But it's not enough, I need more ♪
♪ Nothing seems to satisfy ♪
♪ I said, I don't want it
I just need it ♪
♪ To breathe, to feel, to know I'm alive ♪
♪ Elbow deep inside the borderline ♪
♪ Show me that you love me
And that we belong together ♪
♪ Shoulder deep within the borderline ♪
♪ Relax, turn around and take my hand ♪
[song ends]
-[heart beats]
-[gun fires]
[rocket engine roars]